Guide to the New York State College of Human Ecology Field Study Office records, 1970-1993.
New York State College of Human Ecology Field Study Office records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Human Ecology Field Study Office records, 1970-1993.
23-22-2830
New York State College of Human Ecology.Field Study Office.
4.4 cubic ft.
Financial Records, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Annual reports, Field and International Study Program files, Field Study Committee minutes, long-range plans, grant proposals and logs, course listings, Five Year Plan, and International Educational Committee minutes.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Annual reports, Field and International Study Program files, Field Study Committee minutes, long-range plans, grant proposals and logs, course listings, Five Year Plan, and International Educational Committee minutes. Parts of this collection used to make up collection #23-2-2704
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; New York State College of Human Ecology.International Education Committee.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Field and International Study Program.
Subjects:
Foreign study.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes material from former collection #23-2-2207.
SERIES LIST
Series I. History
Series II. Reports and Handbooks
Series III. Committees and Programs
Series IV. Proposals
Series V. Correspondence
Series VI. Course Material
Series VII. Subject Files
Series VIII. Awards
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. History
  - Human Affairs Program- Report of the First Year, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Human Affairs Program - ID 349, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Human Affairs Program, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Human Resources Administration Seminar, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Human Ecology Field Learning Program, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Human Affairs Program - Nassau County Medical Center, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Evaluation Questionnaire Summary, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Field Study Program Development, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Articles Related to Field Study Issues, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Publicity/Articles, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Publicity/Articles, 1984-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II. Reports and Handbooks
  - Annual Report, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Annual Report, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Annual Report, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Annual Report, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Annual Report, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Annual Report, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Annual Report, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Annual Report, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Annual Report, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Annual Reports - Field and International Study Program and Student Services, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Annual Report, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Annual Report, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Annual Report, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Five Year Plans, 1973-1978, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Field Study Review - New York City, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - New York City Field Study Program - R. Mazur Project, no date (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Survey of the Financial Condition of Field Experience Education, Programs at the Post-Secondary Level, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Field Study Office - Room 159 - Programming Study, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Student Handbooks and Orientation Booklets, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Series III. Committees and Programs
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Interdepartmental Graduate Field in Human Ecology, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Field Experiences Committee, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Field Experiences Committee, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Field Study Committee, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Field Study Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Field Study Committee, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Field Study Committee, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Field Study Committee, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Field Study Committee, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Field Study Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Council - Field Study, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Council - Field Study, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Council - Field Study, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - International Education Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - International Education Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Steering Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Steering Committee, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Steering Committee, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Steering Committee, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Steering Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Program Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Study Abroad Memos, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Study Abroad Memos, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Study Abroad Program, 1985-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Assessment of Study Abroad Programs, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Assessment of Undergraduate Study Abroad Programs in Europe - Mon and Eva Cochran, June 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Establishing a College of Human Ecology in the Philippines, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Study Abroad Experience of Human Ecology Students, 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Series IV. Proposals
  - Rationale for Rural Projects, no date (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Graduate Cooperative Education, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Higher Education Reauthorization College Work Study Proposal, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - A Feasibility Study of Cornell's Proposed Expansion in New York City, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Workshop - Quality in Experiential Learning, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Proposal for the Organization and Governance of the Field Study Office, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Educating for the 21st Century by Integrating International Education into an Experimental Learning Curriculum, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series V. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, Memos, 1974-1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Alumni Correspondence and Information, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Notes from Former Students, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence - Ken Reardon, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence - Ken Reardon, January-April 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence - Ken Reardon, May-October 1988 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence - Ken Reardon, November-February 1989 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence - Ken Reardon, March-September 1989, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Series VI. Course Material
  - ID 100/FIS 100 - Skills for Learning in the Field, 1981, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - FIS 100 - Skills for Learning in the Field, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ID 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - ID 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ID 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, 1977-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - ID 200 - Case Studies, 1978-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ID 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - ID 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, Spring 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ID 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, Fall 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - FIS 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, Spring 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - FIS 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, Spring 1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - FIS 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, Fall 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - FIS 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, Spring 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - FIS 200 - Group Projects, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - FIS 200 - Preparation for Fieldwork, Spring 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - ID 210/FIS 210 - Preparation for International and Cross-Cultural Experience, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - FIS 210 - Preparation for International and Cross-Cultural Experience, 1989-Spring 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - FIS 210 - Preparation for International and Cross-Cultural Experience, Spring 1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - ID 400 - Data Gathering in the Field, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - FIS 400 - Families in Cross-Cultural Perspective, Spring 1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - ID 402 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - FIS 402 - Ithaca Field Study, Spring 1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - ID/FIS 403 - Facilitating Experiential Learning, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - ID/FIS 405 - The Ecology of Organizations in the Federal System, 1974, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - ID 406 - Sponsored Field Learning/Internships - Course Descriptions, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - ID 406 - Sponsored Field Learning/Internships, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - ID 406 - Sponsored Field Learning - Reconstruction Home Internship, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Upstate Program - Dance Hall Renovation Project, Fall 1979 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Upstate Program - Gateways to the Near Westside Project, Fall 1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Upstate Program - Media Access Center Renovation Project, Fall 1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Upstate Program - Log Reports of Special Project Meetings, Fall 1979 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Upstate Program - Youth Service Team Staff Meeting Minutes, Fall 1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Upstate Program - Wayne County Migrant Program, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Upstate Program - Heart Parcours, Spring 1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - ID 406 - Sponsored Field Learning - Curriculum Guide, Spring 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clinton at the Crossroads - Report prepared by FIS Students, December 1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ID 406 - Sponsored Field Learning/Internships, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - FIS 406 - Sponsored Field Learning/Internships, Spring 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Involvement in Project Development in 400 Courses, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Advocates for the Handicapped Newsletter, Fall 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Goodhope Monitoring and Evaluation System, Fall 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - NCR Cost of Living Study, Fall 1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Near Westside Neighborhood Revitalization, Fall 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Migrant Education Project, Spring 1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Legal, Financial and Employment Services for Displaced Women, Spring 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Pathways Through the Tompkins County Mental Health Network, Spring 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Tompkins County Task Force for Battered Women, Spring 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Faculty Involvement, Spring 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving - Course Descriptions, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - ID 407 - Field Experience in Community Problem Solving, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - ID 408 - The Ecology of Urban Organizations: New York City, 1978-1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - ID 408 - The Ecology of Urban Organizations: New York City - Medical Center Westchester, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - ID 408 - The Ecology of Urban Organizations: New York City - Whirlpool, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - FIS 408 - The Ecology of Urban Organizations: New York City, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - FIS 408 - The Ecology of Urban Organizations: New York City - Memos, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - FIS 408 - The Ecology of Urban Organizations: New York City - Pre-test Evaluations, Spring 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - FIS 408 - The Ecology of Urban Organizations: New York City - Post Test, Spring 1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - ID 409 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations, 197901983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - ID 409 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations - Student Guide, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - ID 409 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations - Class Notes, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - ID 409 and 410 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - ID 409 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations - Student Guide, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - ID 409 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations - Evaluation of the Adolescent Drop-In Program of Suicide Prevention and Crisis Service of Tompkins County, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - ID 409 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations - Assessment of Outpatient Services by Tompkins County Hospital Outpatient Services Task Force - Grace Chao, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - ID 409 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations - Day Care for Sick Kids - A Feasibility Study, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - ID 409 - The Ecology of Rural Organizations, Spring 1988 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - FIS 409 - The Ecology of Organizations in the Upstate Region, Fall 1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - FIS 409 - The Ecology of Organizations in the Upstate Region, Spring 1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - FIS 409 - The Ecology of Organizations in the Upstate Region, Fall 1986-Fall 1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - ID/FIS 410 - Advanced Seminar: Analysis of International Experience, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - FIS 409 and 410, Spring 1991 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Field Study Course Enrollment by Year, 1975-1985 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Students Participating in Field and International Study Program and Placement Lists, 1972-1990 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Photos of Students who did Internships, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Series VII. Subject Files
  - Awards Lists, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Grants, 1977-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - FIPSE Grant, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1980-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Budget Worksheets, 1984-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Scholarships, Funding, 1981-1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Florence Halpern Prize, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Learning Web, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Advising, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Telephone Marketing, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Friends of Field Study, 1984-1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Applying to Field Study Program - Memos, 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Review of Curriculum, including job descriptions, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Supervisors Visit to Campus, October 1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Community Learning and Service Partnership Handbook (CLASP), 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - CLASP Workplace Literacy Demonstration Grant, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - CLASP Publications, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - National Society for Internships and Experiential Education (NSIEE) Meeting Minutes, 1978-1984 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - National Society for Internships and Experiential Education (NSIEE) Annual Meeting, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - NSIEE Executive Committee, May 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - NSIEE Board Meeting, October 1982 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Series VIII. Awards
  - Community and Rural Development Innovator Plaque, September 30, 1991 (Box 4)